Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
(Explosion)
米琪，能听到吗？
(Man) Micky, can you hear me?
能听到吗？
Can you hear me?
米琪
(Girl) 'Micky!'
劲量不要动
Try not to move.
如果你明白我的话就眨眨眼
Blink for "yes" if you understand me.
我是马勒医生，负责给你做手术
I am Dr Muller. I operated on you.
你还记得自己身上所发生的事吗？
Do you remember what happened to you?
一点都记不得？
Nothing at all?
你的名字叫米琪，还记得吗？
Micky, that's your name.
Do you remember?
你觉得疼吗？
Are you in pain?
(Screams)
嘘，没事的
Shh. It's OK.
(Sobs)
我什么时候才能看我的样子
(Micky) When can I see myself?
你的受到严重的损伤导致头骨破裂
(Woman) You suffered severe cranial fractures.
必须将你的大部分脸部和下颚进行重建
You required major reconstruction to your face and jaw.
不过你很幸运
But you were lucky.
这些组织损伤原本可以造成更大的伤害
The tissue damage could have been far more severe.
好了？
OK?
神啊
Oh, my God.
我是谁?
Who am I?
你的名字？
(Woman) 'Your name is?'
我叫米歇尔·迪恩，米琪。
'My name is Michelle Deane, Micky.'
几岁了？
'How old are you?'
20岁
'I'm 20 years old.'
- 住在哪？ - 伦敦
- Where do you live? - London.
你让我一天到晚重复说这些愚蠢的东西
You make me say the same stupid things over and over every day.
我受不了了！
I can't stand it.
我想要离开这
I want to get out of here.
你在9岁那年失去了父母
You lost your parents aged nine.
在一场车祸里。 你安然无恙。
In a car accident. You were unharmed.
之后你一直由埃莉诺阿姨照顾
Your Aunt Elinor took care of you after that.
你的节假日时间都在法国南部度过
You spent your holidays in the south of France.
还记得她吗？
Remember her?
- 她现在在哪？ -  她在火灾之前就去世了。
- Where is she now? - She passed away just before the fire.
那么我是孤单一人
So I'm alone.
不，你有很多朋友
No, you have many friends.
这是茱莉亚，你阿姨的合伙人
This is Julia, your aunt's PA.
你还是孩子的时候她就看过你了
She's known you
since you were a child.
你能认出她吗？
Do you recognise her?
这些都是你的朋友
And these are some of your friends.
你还记得他们吗？
Do you remember them?
不
No.
我可以走了吗？是谁来带我走？
(Micky) 'Am I going away? Who's taking me?'
茱莉亚，你的监护人
(Woman) 'Julia, your guardian.'
米琪
Micky.
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
还记得我吗？
Do you remember me?
不
No.
但我应该
But I want to.
我来带你回家
I've come to take you home.
(Horns blare)
(Pneumatic drill)
(Police siren)
当你父母去世后，你阿姨埃莉诺就叫我来照顾你
When your parents died, your Aunt Elinor asked me to look after you.
你不上学的时候就一直呆在我那
Whenever you weren't at school, you stayed with me.
还记得那些事情吗？
(Julia) Do you remember anything at all?
只是一些一闪而过的片段
(Micky) Just flashes.
- 像什么  -  一些人，一些地方
- Like what? - People, places.
我不知道他们是谁.
'I don't know who they are.
有些时候我只是看到火焰
'Sometimes I just see fire.'
这是你阿姨众多房屋中的一处
One of your aunt's many houses.
当你们发现我的时候我有多糟糕？
How bad was I when you found me?
你整个脸血肉模糊，我还以为你已经死了。
The injuries on your face were so bad, I thought you were dead.
(Phone ringing)
你好，我是杰克。
'Hello? It's Jake.
我听说她回来了
'I hear she's back.'
(Julia sighs)
- 她还没有准备好  -她在这吗？
- 'She's really not ready yet.'
- 'Well, is she there?'
我会告诉她你打过电话了。再见，杰克。
'I'll tell her you called. Goodbye, Jake.'
(Julia hangs LIP)
我不知道是否能记起或者想起
I don't know if I'm remembering or imagining.
他是我男朋友？
Was he my boyfriend?
杰克？其中之一
Jake? One of them.
难道还有好几个  - 当然了。
- There was more than one? - Of course!
- 你很有魅力的 – 不再有了
- You were irresistible. - Not any more.
- 这女孩是谁？- 多米尼卡，多。
- Who's this girl? - Domenica, Do.
- 她是谁？ - 一个朋友
- Who is she? - A friend.
她妈妈是你阿姨的女管家。
Her mother was your aunt's housekeeper.
我能给她打个电话吗？- 我觉得这不是个好主意
- Can we call her? - I don't think that's a good idea.
我的其他朋友怎么了？
What about my other friends?
你真正的朋友们都会理解你需要时间
Your real friends will understand that you need time.
这什么意思？
What do you mean?
当你21岁的时候，你会继承埃莉诺所有的财产。
When you're 21,you will inherit Elinor's entire estate.
- 你应该早就告诉我 – 对不起，我以为你还记得。
- You should have told me. - I'm sorry. I thought you knew.
我什么都不知道。你什么时候才能意识到的？
I know nothing. When are you going to realise?
- 我甚至不知道你是谁！ - 我是你的朋友
- I don't even know who you are! - I'm your friend.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
是的
Yeah.
好了，快点。
Yeah. Come on.
菲茨罗伊广场6号，谢谢。
6 Fitzroy Square, please.
米琪
Micky!
我没想到你会来。为什么不给我回电？
I wasn't expecting to see you. Why didn't you call?
好了，这真是个惊喜。请坐下。
Well, this is a surprise. Please, sit down.
告诉我你怎么样了
Tell me how you're doing.
你是谁？
Who are you?
詹姆斯·钱斯。我是你阿姨的律师。
I'm James Chance. I was your aunt's lawyer.
埃莉诺所有的业务都是我负责。是的，这一定让你很混乱。
I handle all Elinor's business.
Yes, this must be confusing for you.
我得到了一封从这地址寄出的信
I got sent a letter from this address.
杰克寄的。他在这工作。
This is from Jake. He works here.
米琪，茱莉亚知道你在这？
Micky, does Julia know you're here?
让我打个电话给她
Please, let me call her.
你最好不要这么快就独自外出
You shouldn't be out on your own so soon.
我很好。谢谢你。
I'm all right. Thank you.
杰克。
Jake.
是杰克吗？
It is Jake?
米琪
Micky.
看到你太好了。你在这干什么？
It's great to see you. What are you doing here?
我在找你！
Looking for you.
- 我尝试过去联系你 – 我知道
- I tried to get in touch. - I know.
见到你太好了
It's nice to meet you.
- 那些事情我都听说了，还有...  - 是
- I heard about everything and... - Yeah.
我的记忆
My memory.
你现在在做什么，米琪？
What are you doing now, Micky?
你想找个地方聊聊或者喝两杯？
Do you want to go somewhere
and talk, get a drink?
额
Er...
我那地方怎么样？
What about my place?
好的
OK.
我最后一次见到你的时候，你说你再也不想看到我了
Last time I saw you, you said you never wanted to see me again.
你改变主意了我很开心。
I'm glad you changed your mind.
好了，我只知道你的名字
Yeah, well, I only have your word for it.
那么，我听说我们是情侣。
So, I hear we were lovers.
断断续续地
On and off.
我以前曾经有你公寓的钥匙
I used to have some keys to your flat.
- 你应该拿回那些 – 让我看看
- You should have them. - Let me see.
- 这是在哪？ -   Narpin路
- Where is it? - Narpin Road.
Hoxton.
只要你愿意你就可以呆在这
You can stay here if you want.
对我来说你看起来很陌生
You look like a stranger to me.
这没什么理由
I have nothing to go on.
仅仅是我的感觉如何
Just how I feel.
(Winces)
你还记得什么吗？
(Julia) 'Do you remember anything at all?'
只是一些片段
(Micky) 'Just flashes.
一些人，一些地方
'People, places.'
- 我叫米歇尔·迪恩，米琪 - 几岁了？
- 'My name is Michelle Deane, Micky.'
- (Woman) 'How old are you?'
21岁
'I'm 21 years old.'
- 住在哪？ - 伦敦。你让我
- 'Where do you live?' - 'London. You make me say
一天到晚重复说这些愚蠢的东西
'the same stupid things over and over every day.'
你还记得其他什么事吗？
'Do you remember anything else?'
我记得你告诉我的那些
'I remember what you've told me.
I remember what you've told me.'
(Micky cries out in pain)
- 这怎么了？ - 哦，这仍然，这仍然会痛
- What is it? - Oh, it still... It still hurts.
- 别停下，没事的。- 好，别让我笑起来。
- Don't stop, it's OK. - OK. Don't make me laugh.
(Micky laughs)
我不忠诚吗？
Was I unfaithful?
也许吧
Probably.
这是我身上糟糕的地方，对不起。
That was crap of me. I'm sorry.
我了解...但是我猜你很愿意拥有这个。
I know...But I suppose you're worth it.
你可以告诉我让我滚开
You should have told me to fuck off.
告诉我关于多的事情
Tell me about Do.
她总是碍事
She always got in the way.
阿，你在嫉妒
Ah, you were jealous.
我以前确实
I was, yes.
以前是什么意思，发生了什么改变？
What do you mean, "was"? What changed?
对不起
Sorry?
你说你以前嫉妒过
You said you were jealous.
为什么现在不了？
Why not now?
茱莉亚没告诉过你？
Julia didn't tell you?
什么？
What?
米琪，对不起
Micky, I'm sorry.
多在火灾里死了
Do died in the fire.
米琪，他们是怎么跟你说的？
Micky, what did they tell you?
我需要喝点水
I'd like some water.
米琪！
Micky!
等等！
Wait!
米琪！米琪！
Micky! Micky!
亲爱的多
'Dear Do
这么多年后再次和你说话我很高兴
'It's nice to talk to you after, well, too many years.
和你失去联系后我一直很懊悔
'It's a deep regret of mine that I lost touch with you.
埃莉诺
'Elinor.'
5月6日，今天是我生命再次开始的时候
(Do) 'May 6th.Today my life began again.'
不好意思
Excuse me.
米琪！
Micky!
我是多，我们在法国度假的时候
It's Do,from our holidays in France.
多
Do!
上帝啊
Oh. my God!
我不敢相信。见到你太高兴了
I can't believe it.I'm so pleased to see you.
- 你在伦敦多久了？ - 一年了，我在家银行上班
- Have you been in London long?  - A year. I work in a bank.
见到你我也很高兴了
I'm so pleased to see you too.
现在你在干嘛？想要去喝点咖啡或者酒吗？
Listen, what are you doing now? Do you want to get a coffee or a drink?
不行，我必须马上回去。
I can't. I've got to get back.
好吧，恩
OK, um...
- 那么，今晚，有空吗？ - 有
- Well, tonight, are you free? - Yeah.
是么？好的  我会给你我的号码
Yeah? OK. Look, I'll give you my number.
你能答应一定会给我来电吗？
Will you promise me you'll call me?
- 当然 – 好的。
- Yeah. - OK.
- 今晚，那时。  -今晚
- Tonight, then. - Tonight.
- 见到你很高兴  -  你也是
- It's so good to see you. - You too.
嗨，这是米琪
'Hey, this is Micky.
请留言
'Please leave a message.'
米琪
Micky.
我以为你已经忘记了
I thought you'd forgotten.
哪里？
Where?
不，不，我不知道。但我可以找到那。
No, no, I don't know it. But I can find it.
好的
Yeah, OK. OK.
恩，再见
Yeah, bye. Bye.
(♪ JAMES BLAKE: "Lindisfarne ll")
(Buzzer)
嗨，进来。
Hey. Come in. Come in.
对不起。我没注意时间。
I'm sorry. I lost track of time.
- 谢谢，你找好了么？ - 是的
- Cheers. Did you find it OK?
- Yeah.
- 是吗？哦，等等
- Yeah? Oh, hang on. - (Phone rings)
你好？
Hello?
耶
Yeah.
不，不，现在不太好
No. No, now's not good.
我知道
I know.
我知道，但是有些事情已经发生了
I know, but something came up.
耶
Yeah.
对不起。我把相片拿走了
I'm sorry. I was taking photographs.
截稿期限就要到了。我必须今晚完成这些工作
I have a deadline. I have to finish them tonight.
我一会再打给你，好么？
I'll call you soon, OK?
- 我工作的时间不应该喝酒。- 你想要我离开吗？
- I shouldn't drink when I'm working. - Do you want me to leave?
不，你可以在这过夜如果你不介意的话
No, you can sleep here if you like.
(♪ THE CHEMICAL BROTHERS:
"Swoon")
你来了!
You came!
你看上去很艳丽
You look gorgeous.
看看你
Look at you.
- 想要来支舞吗？ - 额…好的。
- Do you want to come for a dance? - Um... yeah.
好啊，一，二，三…
OK, one, two, three...
干杯
Cheers.
- 嘿 – 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 这是杰克。我的律师 –哦，真的啊？
- This is Jake. He's my lawyer. - Oh, really?
我以为我是个音乐剧演员
I thought I was the song-and-dance man.
嗨，我是多米尼克，多。
Hi. I'm Domenica, Do.
那么你就是那个丢失了好久的朋友？
So you're the long-lost friend?
我讨厌我的头发。我想把它们都剪了。你还记得那个游戏？
I hate my hair. I want to cut it all off. Do you remember that game?
如果你可以改变你身上的某样东西
If there was one thing you could change about yourself...
- 大部分人是想要变得更好 –去喝点酒
- Most guys want to be better endowed. - Go and get drinks.
怎么样？
All right?
来这。
Come here.
那么，你改变了什么，多？
So, what would you change, Do?
- 哎呀，我不知道从哪开始。- 我想我要改变我的鼻子
- Gosh, I don't know where to start. - I think I'd change my nose.
我想要一个和你那样的
I'd like one like yours.
神啊，都过去这么久了。我们那时是那么亲密
God, it's been so long.We were really close.
- 你还记得？- 是啊。所有照片我都留着。
- Do you remember? - Yeah. I kept all the photos.
- 真的吗？ - 它们都在我的公寓里
- Really? - They're at my flat.
不是吧
No way.
如果你喜欢，我可以找出它们
I could go get them, if you like.
- 什么，现在吗？ - 是啊。为什么不？
- What, now? - Yeah. Why not?
- 这太疯狂了。 - 你会一直在这的，对吗？
- That's crazy. - You'll still be here, right?
克拉彭，谢谢。
Clapham, please.
你没这么容易甩了我
You can't get rid of me that easily.
(♪ CAT'S EYES:
"The Best Person I Know")
(Do) Anywhere here is fine, thanks.
- 在这等等  - 不，我想和你一起
- (Do) Wait here. - (Micky) No, I want to come with you.
不，不，不，不。那是个糟糕的地方，真的，等等。
(Do) No, no, no, no. It's a terrible place, really. Wait.
我来了。
(Micky) I'm coming up.
(Micky) Ah!
之后你们发生了什么？
What happened to you after?
我们回到了英格兰。
We moved back to England.
我母亲在西南部获得了一个工作
My mother got a job in the West Country,
相当偏僻。
miles from anywhere.
我在她死后来到伦敦
And I came up to London after she died.
对于你的离开我很抱歉
I'm sorry you had to go away.
你还和你父亲保持联络吗？
Are you still in touch with your dad?
他自杀了。
He killed himself.
我非常…
I'm so...
非常抱歉。我…
I'm sorry. I've...
我太混蛋了
I've been rubbish.
我应该努力保持联系
I should have tried harder to stay in touch.
都过去了。
It's all right.
看看这个
Look at that.
米琪，停下！我不会游泳
Micky, stop! I can't swim!
我不会游泳
I can't swim!
多！放开我！放开我.我不能呼吸了。
Do! Let go! Let go. I can't breathe.
- 米琪，这太深了！ - 不要。
- Micky, it's too deep! - Don't!
放开我！
Let go!
放开我！我不能呼吸了！
Let go! I can't breathe!
对不起！对不起！
(Micky) I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
米琪，你在干什么？
Micky, what have you done?
- 多！- 对不起！对不起！
- Do! - (Mickey) I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- 我不是有意的！- 没事了。我很好。
- I didn't mean it! - (Do) It's all right. I'm fine.
米琪！米琪！
Micky! Micky!
米琪！
Micky!
- 为什么我不能呆在这？- 多！
- Please! Why can't I stay? - Do!
米琪！
Micky!
多！ 米琪！
" Do! ' Micky!
多！别离开我！
Do! Don't leave me!
- 你要去哪? –哦，我必须去工作了。
- Where are you going? - Oh, I have to go to work.
- 别走。- 但我得去把房租交了。
- Don't go. - But I've got to pay my rent.
你可以搬来和我住。
Yeah? You can move in with me.
好，是，不过我告诉你我现在还不能说，所以...
OK, yeah, but I told you I can't talk right now, so...
好的，听着...不，我一会再给你个电话。
Yeah, OK, listen...No, I'll give you a call back later.
但我现在得马上走了。好吗。
But I have to go now. OK.
再见
Bye.
我阿姨。她甚至不愿意假装喜欢我
My aunt. She doesn't even pretend to like me any more.
她总是在错误的时间找我
She always calls at the wrong time.
我又要迟到了
And I'm going to be late again.
你看到我的包了吗？
Have you seen my bag? OK.
- 晚上再见。- 拜 。
- I'll see you tonight. - Bye.
(Phone rings)
- 你好？ -你好？米琪？
- Hello? - 'Hello? Micky?'
不
No, it...
埃莉诺
Elinor.
嗨，我是多，多米尼卡·劳
Hi. It's Do, Domenica Law.
多？哦，我的神啊！
'Do? Oh, my goodness!'
你和米琪一起多久了？
How long have you been in touch with Micky?
额...哦，也就只有几天。
Um... Oh, just a few days.
我知道了。
I see.
- 埃莉诺？ - 我在听。
- 'Elinor?' - Yes, I'm here.
听着，我会叫米琪给你回电的。
Listen, I'll get Micky to call you.
很高兴再一次和你通话。
'It's so good to speak to you again.'
晚安，多。
Good evening, Do.
你这是什么意思？
What do you mean?
一切都好。不用担心。
It's all right. Don't worry.
- 我得走了 – 不，求你，多。
- I need to go. - No, please, Do.
你现在是米琪了。
You're Micky now.
请让我走。
Please, let me go.
这是我们之间的秘密。
(Julia) 'It's our secret.
多？多？
'Do? Do?'
今天是我生命再次开始的时候
(Do) 'Today my life began again.'
这是我们之间的秘密
(Julia) 'It's our secret.'
五月，星期一...
(Do) 'Monday, May...
午后我们一起呆在她的公寓里
'We sat in her apartment together for the rest of the afternoon.
没人理解我们之间分享的东西
'Nobody understands what we share.
6月2日 礼拜六
'Saturday June 2nd.
她不需要他
'She doesn't need him.
她只需要我
'She only needs me.
没人能像她一样了解我。
'Nobody understands me like she does.
我想要和她一样
'I'd love to be like her.
她只需要我
'She only needs me.
没人理解我们之间分享的东西
'Nobody understands what we share.'
不能在这睡觉，亲爱的。
Can't sleep here, love.
楼上，穿过那2间门，左边第一个。
Upstairs, through the double doors, first on the left.
请你12小时后取消你的房间，劳小姐。
Please vacate your room by 12, Miss Law.
- 你叫我什么？ - 劳小姐。
- What did you call me? - Miss Law.
难道有问题？
Isn't it?
今天是另一个愉快的日子
(Do) 'Today was another glorious day.'
(♪ CRYSTAL FIGHTERS:
"At Home")
我不敢相信她愿意花那么多时间和我一起。
'I can't believe she wants to spend so much time with me.'
这看上去很好。
It looks OK.
没人像她一样了解我
'Nobody understands me like she does.
没人了解我们之间分享的东西。
'Nobody knows what we share.'
再见，别恨我。
Bye. Don't hate me.
对不起迟到了，宝贝。
Sorry I'm late, babe.
我一会再打给你，多，好吗？
I'll call you, Do, OK?
再见。
See you.
(Moaning)
Hi.
(Micky) Ohh!
谢谢。
Thanks.
(Moaning)
- 对不起 – 你还好吗？
- (Do) Sorry. - You all right?
恩，还好。
Yeah, fine.
亲爱的劳
(Elinor) 'Dear Do.
这些小东西我想也有有点帮助
'A small something.I hope it helps.
埃莉诺
'Elinor.'
亲爱的埃莉诺
(Do) 'Dear Elinor.
一直以来，和你交谈总是那么美妙
'It was so wonderful to talk to you after all this time
我很高兴收到你的来信
'and I was so delighted to receive your letter.
在你来电之后我觉得自己很迟钝，因为我想要说的话太多了
'I felt so stupid after your call because I wanted to say so much,
但又不知道从哪里开始说起
'but I just didn't know where to start.
我可以告诉你一些米琪的消息。
'And I can give you news of Micky.
她太忙了，她都没有她想要的
'She's so busy she doesn't have the opportunity
足够的写作条件
'to write as much as she'd like to.'
你怎么看？
How's that for you?
我亲爱的多，
(Elinor) 'My dearest Do,
谢谢你友好又体贴的来信
'thank you for your kind and considerate letter.
在这么多年后听到你的声音
'It was such a pleasant surprise to hear your voice
真是让我出奇的愉快
'after so many years.'
你看上去很好。
You look good.
(♪ JOKER: "The Vision")
Lighten up.
- 哦，大家准备要走了？ - 拜，下次再见。
- Oh, are you guys going? - Bye, see you later.
对不起，女士。 你还有其他的卡吗？
I'm sorry, madam.
Have you got another card?
我来吧
I'll do it.
- 别傻了，你都没钱了。 - 哦，这就是她为什么从来不付钱的原因？
- Don't be stupid, you're broke. - Oh, is that why he never pays?
- 我听到了什么？ - 只不过我刚了解到些事情
- Am I hearing this? - It's just something I've picked up on.
你就是该死的寄生虫。
You're the fucking parasite.
- 你怎么能这么说？ - 那好，你为什么要忍受这个？
- How can you say that? - Well, why do you put up with it?
你一点都不在乎钱但你的朋友对钱可很迷恋。
You don't give a shit about money but your friends are obsessed with it.
你有什么毛病啊？
What's wrong with you?
你知道什么？我得走了。
Do you know what? I need to go.
杰克！
Jake!
下一次看到你的时候最好她不在身旁。
Next time it would be nice to see you without her around.
滚开
Get off.
(♪ CRYSTAL FIGHTERS: "Follow")
- 你现在高兴了？ - 对不起。
- Are you happy now? - I'm sorry.
- 对不起 – 你总是在说对不起
- I'm sorry. - You always say you're sorry.
你说得太多了
You say it too much.
我爱你
I love you.
真的？
Do you?
你是认真的？
Do you really?
这不正是你想要的？
Is this what you want?
- 离我远点 – 这不正是你想要的，多？
- Get off me. - Is that what you want, Do?
滚开
Get off.
现在高兴了？
Happy now?
滚出去！
Get out!
亲爱的埃莉诺，我告诉你我写了些关于米琪的消息
'Dear Elinor, I told you I'd write with news of Micky.
她无疑很享受自己的生活
'She certainly lives her life to the full,
但有些时候也许过头了
'maybe too much sometimes.
她和她的那群人经常晚上出去
'She and her crowd stay out all night most of the time.
有些时候我很担心她
'I can't pretend I don't worry about her sometimes.
希望我能快点见到你
'Hopefully I'll get to meet you soon
这样我就能亲自为拥有这几个宝贵的夏季
'and I'll be able to thank you in person
而感谢你
'for all those precious summers.
献上最温柔最美好的祝福，多。
'With warmest best wishes, Do.'
发生什么了？
What happened?
日子到这里就结束了
The diary entries just stop.
如果我是多，那为什么你们要告诉我我是米琪
If I'm Do, then why did you tell me I was Micky?
我在你们争吵后的一个早晨到达那里
I arrived the morning after one of your fights.
我能从你们的脸上看出来
I could see it in your face.
很明显你踩过线了，事情无法回头。
It was clear you'd crossed a line. There was no going back.
你只是没有意识到。
You just didn't realise it.
你最后一次见过埃莉诺后她的健康状况越来越糟
Elinor's health has taken a turn for the worse since you last saw her.
她在医院里病得很厉害
She's very ill in hospital.
抱歉，但是她只剩几个星期的日子了
I'm sorry, but they give her no more than a few weeks.
她希望你马上去法国见她
She wants you to visit her in France right away.
你们两个都去 多，请准备好行囊
Both of you. Do, please pack a bag.
- 不，别听她的，多。          - 她一样想见到多
- No, don't listen to her, Do. - She wants to see Do too.
- 你不能把她差来差去。             - 准备好你的行囊
- You can't just order her around. - Pack your bag, please.
我不会去的。她恨我。
I'm not going. She hates me.
- 你这贱人！  - 米琪！
- You bitch!  - Micky!
米琪，住手！
Micky, stop it!
米琪
Micky!
我只是去了洗手间。
I'm just going to go to the bathroom.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
因为你在自欺欺人
Because your mind is blocking it out.
我不是多。
I'm not Do.
我一点都不像她
I don't feel like her.
多在事故中死了
Do died in the accident.
谢谢你邀请我
(Do) 'Thank you for inviting me.'
那么...你想和我谈些什么
So... what do you want to talk to me about?
我想你需要振作起来
I thought you needed cheering up.
不用，我很好
No, I'm fine.
什么，活在米琪的阴影之下
What, living under Micky's shadow?
- 好了，我不想说这些         - 抱歉
- Well, I wouldn't say that. - Sorry.
只是这使我想起了我是怎么到现在这种地步
I was just reminded of how it was for me.
我不知道我怎么能够忍耐如此长的时间
I don't know how I put up with it for so long.
- 先是埃莉诺然后是米琪         - 你们俩合不来，是吗？
- First Elinor and then Micky. - You two don't get on, do you?
不，米琪魅力非凡
No. Micky is irresistible.
但是她在自我放纵。 小心些不要最后被她所伤害
But she's destroying herself. Be careful you don't end up getting hurt.
我是她的朋友
I'm her friend.
她不会伤害我
So she won't hurt me.
也许你是对的 只是给你一点忠告
No, you're probably right. Just a little warning.
我看过你写给埃莉诺的信
I've read your letters to Elinor.
- 你看过我的信            -抱歉，这是我工作的一部分
- You've read my letters? - Sorry. It's part of my job.
-你怎么可以     - 多
- How dare you? - Do...
我知道你为什么把支票退回给埃莉诺
I know why you returned the cheque to Elinor.
你一定觉得羞耻
You mustn't feel ashamed.
我真的觉得这不是个好想法
I really don't think this was such a good idea.
我只是觉得这非常不公平
I just think it is so unfair.
为什么我们得不到我们人生应得的
Why do we not get the life we deserve?
她亲自找到我，当我还是18岁在她的一家
When I was 18, I was working in one of Elinor's factories
工厂工作的时候
and she saw something in me.
她给了我一切
She offered me everything.
接着米琪来了
Then along came Micky.
实际上你就和我一样
Deep down you're just like me.
你知道你应该得到一个更好的人生
You know you should have a better life.
说服米琪去法国南部
(Julia) 'Persuade Micky to come to the south of France.
这样对你俩都有好处
'It will be the best for both of you.'
我
I've...
我要搬回我自己的公寓
I've moved back to my own flat.
给我个电话等你们都到的时候
Now, when you both get there, give me a call.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
(Doorbell)
- 准备行囊        - 什么？
- Pack your bags. - What?
你要带上你的游泳衣和护照
You need your swimsuit and your passport.
护照
Passport?
我想也许我们可以去法国南部
I thought maybe we could go to the south of France.
我需要个改变同时我们可以去看看埃莉诺
I need a break and we could see Elinor.
- 好，但我以为你             - 我改变主意了
- Yeah, but I thought you... - Yeah, I changed my mind.
瞧，她一定会很高兴你能去，我们可以飞去巴黎再租辆车
Look, she'd love you to come and we can fly to Paris, hire a car,
欣赏一路的美景
take the scenic route.
快点
Come on.
我来帮你整理
I'll help you pack.
(♪ PAULINE CROZE: "T'es Beau")
我只是讨厌和她在一起时她要我扮演的角色
I just hate myself when I'm with her, the way she makes me act.
为什么你能忍受这些
Why do you put up with it, then?
哦
Oh...
这好复杂
It's complicated.
茱莉亚比任何人都更用心抚育我
Julia brought me up as much as anyone.
某一点上，埃莉诺只是放弃我而已
At a certain point, Elinor just gave up on me.
换首歌
Change the music, DJ.
那么，杰克对我们要走是什么看法
So, what did Jake say about us coming away?
- 还没跟他说             - 你还要和他在一起吗？
- Haven't spoken to him. - Are you going to stay with him?
如果他还非常想要我
If he wants me enough.
(♪ METRONOMY: "The Bay")
你一定是心烦意乱了。开到这里来了
(Do) You must be shattered. Pull in here.
- 是这样吗？
- Will this do? - (Do laughs)
Wow!
神啊，你要是再多开几步我们就会
Christ, if you'd driven a few more feet,
we would have...
胡扯
Shit!
哇
Wow!
快来
Come on.
- 她准备好了  - 谢谢你
- She's ready. - Thank you.
埃莉诺你好
Hello, Elinor.
Hi, Elinor.
埃莉诺，这是多。
It's Do, Elinor.
我不是米琪
I'm not Micky.
我在这，我是米琪
I'm Micky. I'm here.
你好
Bonjour.
你一定是多
You must be Do.
- 你好     - 你好？
- Bonjour. - Ca va?
她睡着了
She's sleeping.
- 米琪！你好    - 伊薇特！你还好吗？
- Micky! Ca va? - Yvette! Comment ca va?
- 我很好      - 我也很好
- Ca va bien? - Ca va bien.
很高兴见到你
I'm pleased to see you.
多，快点。
Do, come on.
把我们的行囊放在这然后一起去海滩
Let's just dump our stuff here
and go straight to the beach.
脚踢起来
Kick your feet.
双臂伸展
Arms out.
(Phone rings)
你好
Hello.
我不会再打一次所以听好了
I'm not going to call again so please listen.
我只是想让你诚实面对你自己所想要的东西
I just want you to be honest with yourself about what you want.
我想要她
I want her.
她已经毁掉过一次你的生活了
She's ruined your life once already.
是米琪告诉你母亲关于你父亲和埃莉诺的风流韵事
'Micky told your mother about your father's affair with Elinor.
这一定和他的自杀有些关系
'Surely that must have something to do with why he committed suicide.'
米琪
Micky!
别离开我
Don't leave me!
(crying)
她从来没有像你爱她那样爱过你
'She'll never love you in the way you want her to.
这不是她要的 现在 仔细听我说
'It's not in her nature. Now, listen carefully to me.
这是你必须要要做的
'This is what you have to do.'
你昨天出去了好久 我去海滩了
You were gone ages yesterday. I went to the beach.
村子里有什么活动？
Was there any action in the village?
社交活动
Party central.
对了，这空了。
Right, it's empty.
- 我来    -别，别
- My turn. - No, no, no.
该死
Shit.
- 一切都好          -  是的，谢谢你
- Is everything OK? - Yes, thank you.
我会做的
I'll do it.
多
(Micky) Do?
干什么这么久啊 我服了你了 有什么状况吗
What took you so long? I gave up on you. Anything wrong?
没事 只是那阳光 把我晃昏了
No. It's just the sun. It's knocked me out.
(Screams)
(Sobs)
(♪ NOUVELLE VAGUE:
"Love Will Tear Us Apart")
我希望那阳光就停到这刚刚好
I wish the sun would just stop right there,
别再照到其他地方
not move any more.
然后我会永远这样躺着
(Sighs) Then I'd just lay like this forever.
你呢，多
What about you, Do?
你有想过未来吗
Do you think about the future?
天啊，这么热的情况下根本没法去想其他事情
Gosh, it's too hot to think about anything.
我也不想去想这些
I don't want to think about it either.
你晚上想要一起出去吗？ 某人的小艇那有个聚会
Do you want to go out tonight? There's a party on some guy's boat.
- 什么人 是朋友吗     - 我不知道 就是某个家伙
- What guy? A friend? - I don't know. It's just some guy.
你应该学会游泳
You should learn to swim.
快来 我们一起去小艇 快点
(French boy) Come on. Let's go to the boat! Come on!
- 我们去小艇了，你来吗         -  你也来吗
- We go to the boat. You come? - Yeah. Are you coming?
额，我想你的小艇一定很大
(Do) Er, I thought you had a big boat.
- 那就是                - 哦
- Well, that's his boat. - Oh.
我们不用带上她，不是吗
We don't need to bring her, do we?
(Cheering and laughing)
(Boat engine revving)
(Chatter and laughter)
(♪ CRYSTAL CASTLES:
"Celestica")
- 你在这干什么           - 米琪，抱歉
- What are you doing here? - Micky, I'm sorry.
我刚得到一些你阿姨的坏消息
I've got some bad news about your aunt.
她昨天去世了
She passed away yesterday.
结束了 快点
C'est fini. Come on.
她现在很平静
She's quiet now.
告诉我该做什么
Tell me what to do.
不是在这
Not here.
7月4日 你的生日那天
On 4th July, your birthday,
你会有个晚宴 还有一些庆祝活动
you'll go out for dinner,have a little celebration.
这看上去就像是自然发生的  那晚上这些事情就会发生
That will seem natural aftewvards. That's the night it will happen.
你的计划不会成功的
Your plan will never work.
火灾会造成非常严重的损害 他们会以为是锅炉是罪魁祸首
The fire will cause so much damage they'll assume it was the boiler.
他们不会发现有人切断煤气管道
They'll never discover the disconnected gas pipe.
如果我死了，这是我应得的
If I die, I'll deserve it.
你必须在凌晨一点制造火灾
You have to start the fire at 1:00am.
我们必须确定好时间这样我才能第一时间达到
We need to agree a time so that I can be the first to arrive.
我们不会那么容易成功的
We'll never get away with this.
伊薇特怎么办 她会认出我的
What about Yvette? She'll recognise me.
这不可能的
That will be impossible.
我们会去瑞士
We'll go to Switzerland.
他们很专业 他们有最好的外科手术医师
They're very discreet. They have the best surgical facilities.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
你会变成米琪
You will be Micky.
你要我换一张脸
Do you want me to change my face?
我了解
I know.
但这一切都是值得的
But it will be worth it.
当机会到来的时候
Sometimes you get a chance,
你抓住了它 你就可以永远地改变自己的人生
and if you seize it in that moment, you can change your life forever.
如果你错过了，那它就一去不复返
If you let it slip... it will be gone.
(♪ PETER SARSTEDT:
"Where Do You Go To My Lovely?")
和我一起
Come with me.
(Laughing)
- 看    -神啊 我们会嗑高得
- Look. - Christ, we'll be out of it.
- 我来驾驶           - 只是开个车而已，快点
- I've got to drive. - Just leave the car. Come on.
- 好的，就一下        - 好
- All right, just one. - OK.
真的？
Ready?
对，我们走
Right, let's go.
(♪ CASSIUS: "Toop Toop")
不，别让我
No, don't make me...
- 我们能走了吗      - 这才刚开始
- Can we leave now? - It's just getting started.
真的  这已经是他第三回开始讲那些故事
Really? It's the third time he's started to tell that story
而且一点都不好笑
and it's not getting any funnier.
好把 五分钟
OK, five minutes.
请
Please.
好的
OK.
干杯
A la tienne!
快点，上床上来
Come on, get into bed.
(Hissing)
(Explosion)
起作用了 比期望的要好
It worked, better than expected.
你那可怜的面庞在摔破后已经变得难以辨认
Your poor face, it was unrecognisable after the fall.
但即便这也也对我们有利
But even that worked to our advantage.
- 还有失忆          - 神啊
- And the amnesia... - Oh, my God.
我都做了些什么  我怎么能做出这些事情
What have I done? How could I have gone through with it?
- 冷静下来 多        - 我会去报警
- Do, calm yourself. - I'm going to the police.
为什么 你已经得到了一切你想要的
Why? You've got everything you ever wanted.
我不想要这些
I didn't want this.
- 我不要这些         - 原来的米琪已经不在了
- I don't want this. - The old Micky is gone.
你现在才是米琪
You're Micky now.
假如律师也相信你
And if the lawyer believes you,as he does,
那么所有人都会
then everyone will.
我们就可以回到法国南部埃莉诺的地方
We'll go back to Elinor's in the south of France.
我们会等待遗嘱的宣读
We'll wait for the reading of the will.
现在你已经安全了
Here. You're safe now.
你是谁？
Who are you?
1963 E-Type.
这很漂亮，不是么
It's a beauty, isn't it?
如果我有10万块钱就可以买给你
I'd buy it off you if I had a spare 100,000 euros.
但是 那时 你并不需要钱
But, then, you don't need the money.
- 让我们进去吧  - 你想要什么
- Let's get in. - What do you want?
告诉你一个故事
To tell you a story.
这是个私人海滩
This is a private beach.
我要去游个泳
I'm going for a swim.
事实上，我不是为阳光而来
Actually, I'm not here for the sun.
我知道你在这想要什么
I know what you're here for.
你朋友去过咖啡店那
Your friend stopped at the café.
当她要给英格兰去电的时候我非常好奇
I got interested when she wanted to call England.
抱歉     我最好打个电话去伦敦
Excuse me. I'd like to make a call to London.
- 手机找不到了     - 你怎么猜到的
- Lost your phone? - How did you guess?
我偷偷在听
'I listened in.'
她已经毁掉过一次你的生活
(Julia) 'She's ruined your life once already.'
这事情和我有什么关系
(Micky) What does this have to do with me?
他们在计划些什么
They've got some sort of a plan.
对付你
Against you.
她在一个本子上写了些什么
She wrote something on a pad.
记住 楼上的卫生间
(Julia) 'Remember. The upstairs bathroom.
克拉丽莎
'Clarissa.'
这是空白的
It's blank.
她写的时候很用力
She presses too hard when she writes.
这上面说
'It says...'
克拉丽莎(电器的牌子) 楼上的 卫生间
"Clarissa upstairs bathroom."
多少钱
How much?
1千
A thousand?
明天11点我们再见
Meet me at the tabac, tomorrow at 11:00.
你昨天出去很长时间了
You were gone for ages yesterday.
我去海滩了
I went to the beach.
- 村里有什么活动吗？                   - 社交聚会
- Was there any action in the village? - Party central.
对了，这空了
Right, it's empty.
- 让我来   - 别  别 别 我去就好
- My turn. - No, no, no. I'll go.
多
'Do?'
怎么这么长时间        我服了你了   出什么状况了
What took you so long? I gave up on you. Anything wrong?
没，只是太阳 把我晃昏了
No. It's just the sun. It's knocked me out.
这里是500
There's 500.
其他的呢
Where is the rest?
你会得到的 如果你说的东西确实很有意思
If what you have to say is interesting, you'll get the rest.
他们要做的就是松开接头
All they have to do is loosen the joint
在一个封闭的房间里制造明火
and in a closed room with a naked flame...
我剩下的钱在哪？
Where is the rest of my money?
这里是剩下的
That was the rest.
你很幸运碰到了我 我可是物超所值
You're lucky to have a taste of me. I'm worth much more than that.
我不再需要你了
I don't need you any more.
你欠我的
You owe me.
你应该学会游泳
You should learn to swim.
- 为什么我要相信你                  - 我们有过交易，但你杀了她
- (Micky) Why should I believe you? - We had a deal, but you killed her.
所以交易不一样了 现在我要更多的钱
So the deal is different and now I want more money.
请让我走
Let me go. Please.
你没得讨价还价
You're not in a position to bargain.
你想要多少
How much do you want?
10万
100,000.
100,000?
好
OK.
只要记住 一个电话就可以毁掉你
Just remember, one phone call will finish you.
你还记得发生了什么
(Dr Muller) 'Do you remember what happened to you?'
你的名字叫米琪
Micky, that's your name.
你还记得吗
'Do you remember?'
劳女士
(Receptionist) Miss Law.
有问题吗
Isn't it?
你的名字叫米琪
(Dr Muller) 'Micky, that's your name.'
晚上好，多
(Julia) 'Good evening, Do.'
我是谁
(Micky) 'Who am I?'
多米尼卡... 米琪 ...多
(Julia) 'Domenica... Micky... Do.'
我们会找出来的
We've been found out.
咖啡店那男孩说他全都听到了
The boy from the café, says he's heard it all.
- 他怎么做到的  - 我不知道
- How could he? - I don't know.
伊薇特看到他在附近
Yvette's seen him snooping around.
你都告诉了他什么
What did you tell him?
- 我没有告诉他真相                   - 真相
- Well, I didn't tell him the truth. - The truth?
我没有告诉她你和多密谋要杀害米琪
I didn't tell him that you plotted with Do to kill Micky.
还好
Just as well.
明天是米琪21岁生日
Tomorrow is Micky's 21st birthday.
我去伦敦和钱斯见面，最终我们会看到遗嘱
I'm meeting Chance in London and at last we'll read the will.
没有看到米琪真是遗憾
(Chance) I'm sorry not to have seen Micky.
她余下的事情都做得很好
The rest is doing her good.
我非常惊讶你居然不是遗嘱的
I was surprised that you were not made an executor,
执行人或者是受益人
or a beneficiary, indeed.
也许她为你准备好了其他条款
Perhaps she'd already made provision for you.
这一段时间可以做些适当的调整
There's been an arrangement in place for some time.
一份不错的养老金
A modest pension.
- 我没有告诉他真相               - 真相
- 'I didn't tell him the truth.' - 'The truth?'
我没有告诉他你和多密谋杀害米琪
'I didn't tell him that you plotted with Do to kill Micky.'
还
'Just...'
这部分和五年前起草时没有多大变化
There had been no change to the will drafted five years ago,
只有这些 最后条款的内容 一定要等到米琪生日那天才能被宣读
just this, the last detail, to be opened on Micky's birthday.
顺带祝米琪生日快乐
Happy birthday to Micky, by the way.
- 我的钱在哪        - 你会拿到的
- Where's my money? - You'll get your money.
我们去兜会风
Let's go for a drive.
如果你能闭紧你的嘴巴这些就是你的了
It's yours if you can keep your mouth shut.
你说这值10万
You said it's worth 100,000.
你可以把它卖了只要你想这么做
You could sell it if you want.
茱莉亚
Julia?
有人吗 茱莉亚
Hello? Julia?
你在这吗
Are you there?
茱莉亚
Julia?
有人在这吗
Is anyone here?
有人吗
Hello?
那老妇人最后的决定
The old lady had the last word.
我根本没猜到
I would never have guessed.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
她把一切都给了你
She left everything to you.
- 给我   - 给你
- To me? - To you.
她把所有东西都给了多米尼卡·劳
She left everything to Domenica Law.
所有的一切
All this for nothing.
- 米琪死了  - 米琪知道这一切 茱莉亚
- And Micky dead. - Micky knew, Julia.
不
No.
不 她什么都不知道
No, she knew nothing.
如果她知道你根本就不会在这，多
Do, you wouldn't be here if she'd known.
她
She...
她想要阻止你
She would have stopped you.
你不可能
You can't...
- 你不可能是米琪      - 都结束了
- You can't be Micky! - It's over.
我录下了你承认谋杀的对话 我已经把带子寄给了钱斯
I recorded you admitting to murder. I sent the tape to Chance.
让我走 我不能呼吸了
Let go! I can't breathe!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
跑
Run!
和我一起
Come with me.
- 和我一起     - 不 不
- Come with me!- No! No!
不
No!
(Screams)
米琪 快跑
Run, Micky!
快跑
Run!
多 和我一起
Do, come with me!
跑 快跑
Run! Run!
我是米琪 我就是米琪
I'm Micky! I'm Micky!
(Sobbing)
(♪ CRYSTAL FIGHTERS:
"At Home")
♪ Remember how I said
I'd come some day, baby
♪ How I said I'd come around
to see you one day
♪ I said I'd try to find a way to run away,
I'd get away some day
♪ Gonna come some day, baby
♪ Gonna fly around the world
to hear you say
♪ I'm gonna fly around the world
to try to find you again and say
♪ I never thought I'd see you again
♪ I never thought
I'd get to be with my best friend
♪ Never thought I'd have to tell you again
I Never thought I'd have to tell you
how I lost my mind again
♪ I left alone
♪ I left the world, I was running
♪ To be by your side
♪ I was dying
♪ Alone by your side
♪ I was flying
♪ I came alone
♪ I've come a long way to get here
♪ The leaves that fall to my feet
♪ At home
♪ They mean nothing to me...♪
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player